It's the coolest job ever.
The Sorcerer's Apprentice is a fantasy, adventure,
action film directed by Jon Turteltaub.
Balthazar Blake is a master sorcerer in modern-day Manhattan trying to
defend the city from his arch-nemesis, Maxim Horvath.
Balthazar can't do it alone, so he recruits Dave Stutler, a seemingly average
guy who demonstrates hidden potential, as his reluctant protégé.
The sorcerer gives his unwilling accomplice a crash course in the art and science of magic,
and together, these unlikely partners work to stop the forces of darkness.
Balthazar Blake, played by Nicolas Cage.
David "Dave" Stutler, played by Jay Baruchel.
Maxim Horvath, played by Alfred Molina.
Rebecca "Becky" Barnes, played by Teresa Palmer.
Drake Stone, played by Toby Kebbell.
Bennet Zurrow, played by Omar Benson Miller.
The Sorcerer's Apprentice is a 2010 American action adventure
fantasy film directed by Jon Turteltaub, from a screenplay by Matt Lopez
and the writing team of Doug Miro and Carlo Bernard, and a screen story by Lopez, Lawrence Konner, and Mark Rosenthal.
The film stars Nicolas Cage as Balthazar Blake, a sorcerer who is tasked with training Dave Stutler, played by Jay
Baruchel, the heir of Merlin and the only one with the power to stop an evil sorceress from rising again.
Alfred Molina, Teresa Palmer, and Monica Bellucci star in supporting roles.
The film is produced by Walt Disney Pictures, Jerry Bruckheimer
Films, Saturn Films, and Broken Road Productions.
The story is adapted from a segment in the 1940 Disney film Fantasia, entitled "The Sorcerer's Apprentice", featuring Mickey Mouse (with one scene being an extensive
reference to it), which in turn is based on the late-1890s symphonic poem by Paul Dukas, itself derived from the 1797 Johann Wolfgang von Goethe ballad.
The Sorcerer's Apprentice made its premiere at the Fantasia Film Festival on July 8, 2010, and was
theatrically released by Walt Disney Studios Motion Pictures in the United States on July 14.
The film received mixed reviews from critics and was a box-office bomb,
grossing only $215 million against a $150 million budget.
The film explores themes of witch, mission, magic, mystic, castle.
The tone is dark.